

Arlington, VA 22201, United States

□ (+1) 312-478-1131 | 🗷 abose@kmb.ac | 🌴 www.arindambose.com | 🖸 arindam-bose | 🛅 arindam-bose-75425417

Summary.

Currently working as a research engineer at KMB Telematics Inc. where we are making radar sensors for automotive cars. Finished Ph.D. in Electrical Engineering from the University of Illinois at Chicago under supervision of Prof. Mojtaba Soltanalian at WaveOPT lab. Research interests include FMCW radar, MIMO radar, radar signal processing, statistical signal processing, optimization theory, machine learning, active sensing. Always interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies.

Work Experience _____

KMB Telematics Inc. Arlington, VA, USA

SENIOR RESEARCH ENGINEER, RADAR SIGNAL PROCESSING

Oct. 2020 - Present

SENIOR RESEARCH INTERN. RADAR SIGNAL PROCESSING

May 2019 - Aug. 2020

- · Developing the digital design of a high performance automotive MIMO radar system using cutting edge FPGAs, MCUs and MPUs
- Implementing sophisticated algorithms for antenna array designing for automotive MIMO radar

University of Illinois at Chicago

Chicago, IL, USA

RESEARCH ASSISTANT, WAVEOPT LAB, DEPARTMENT OF ELECTRICAL AND COMPUTER ENGINEERING

May 2016 - Dec. 2020

- · Developed various non-convex optimization algorithms for waveform synthesis for active sensing systems
- Assisted and collaborated with Dr. M. Soltanalian in signal processing and optimization theory research and working towards PhD thesis

TEACHING ASSISTANT, DEPARTMENT OF ELECTRICAL AND COMPUTER ENGINEERING AND DEPARTMENT OF PHYSICS

Aug. 2015 - May 2020

· Courses assisted: Digital signal processing, Statistical signal processing, Image analysis and computer vision, Introductory physics, General physics

Mitsubishi Electric Research Laboratories

Cambridge, MA, USA

SUMMER INTERN, SIGNAL PROCESSING GROUP

May 2018 - Aug. 2018

• Developed efficient algorithms for Time-Domain Spectroscopy systems using THz

Cognizant Technology Solutions Pvt. Ltd.

Kolkata, India

PROGRAMMER ANALYST, HEALTH CARE PRACTICE

Apr. 2013 - Jul. 2014

- Developed and maintained several Java based web projects according to client requests
- · Designed web services and complex web pages in JSP, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript

Education

University of Illinois at Chicago

Chicago, IL, USA

PHD IN ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING

MS IN ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING

2020

· Thesis title: Waveform synthesis for active sensing with emerging applications (Advisor: Dr. Mojtaba Soltanalian)

West Bengal University of Technology

Kolkata, India

B.Tech in Electronics and Communication Engineering

2012

· Thesis topic: Efficient algorithms for digital watermarking (Advisor: Dr. Somnath Maiti)

Publications

MAJOR JOURNAL PAPERS

Waveform Design for Mutual Interference Mitigation in Automotive Radar

A. BOSE, B. TANG, W. HUANG, M. SOLTANALIAN, AND J. LI

2022

arXiv preprint arXiv:2208.04398

Mutual Interference Mitigation for Multiple Connected Automotive Radar Systems

A. BOSE, B. TANG, M. SOLTANALIAN, AND J. LI

2021

Published in IEEE Transactions on Vehicular Technology, vol. 70, no. 10, Oct. 2021

Efficient Waveform Covariance Matrix Design and Antenna Selection for MIMO Radar	
A. Bose, S. Khobahi, and M. Soltanalian	2020
Published in Elsevier Journal of Signal Processing, vol. 183, Jun. 2021	
One-Bit Radar Processing With Time-Varying Sampling Thresholds	
A. Ameri, A. Bose , J. Li, and M. Soltanalian	2019
Published in IEEE Transactions on Signal Processing	
Constructing Binary Sequences With Good Correlation Properties: An Efficient Analytical-Computational Interplay	
A. Bose, M. Soltanalian	2018
Published in IEEE Transactions on Signal Processing	
Major Conference Presentations	
Deep One-Bit Compressive Autoencoding	Rio de Janeiro, Brazil
S. KHOBAHI, A. BOSE, AND M. SOLTANALIAN	Jul. 2021
Presented in Statistical Signal Processing Workshop (SSP) 2021	
Limits of Transmit Beamforming for Massive MIMO Radar	Pacific Grove, CA, USA
A. Bose, A. Ghauri, and M. Soltanalian Presented in IEEE Asilomar Conference on Signals, Systems, and Computers 2020	Nov. 2020
Joint Optimization of Waveform Covariance Matrix and Antenna Selection for MIMO Radar	Pacific Grove, CA, USA
A. Bose, S. Khobahi, and M. Soltanalian	Nov. 2019
Presented in IEEE Asilomar Conference on Signals, Systems, and Computers 2019	
THz Multi-Layer Imaging Via Nonlinear Inverse Scattering	Paris, France
 A. Bose, A. Kadu, H. Mansour, P. Wang, P. Boufounos, P. Orlik, and M. Soltanalian Presented in IEEE International Conference on Infrared, Millimeter, and Terahertz Waves (IRMMW-THz) 2019 	Sep. 2019
Generalized Cyclic Algorithms for Designing Unimodular Sequence Sets with Good	Shoffield IIV
(Complementary) Correlation Properties	Sheffield, UK
 A. Bose, I. A. Arriaga-Trejo, A. G. Orozco-Lugo, and M. Soltanalian Presented in IEEE Sensor Array and Multichannel Signal Processing Workshop (SAM) 2018, July 2018 	Jul. 2018
Low-Rank Matrix Recovery from One-Bit Comparison Information	Calgary, Canada
A. Bose, A. Ameri, M. Klug, M. Soltanalian	Apr. 2018
• Presenting in 43rd IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech and Signal Processing (ICASSP), April 2018	
Designing Signals with Good Correlation and Distribution Properties	Calgary, AB, Canada
A. Bose, N. Mohammadi, M. Soltanalian	Apr. 2018
Presenting in 43rd IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech and Signal Processing (ICASSP), April 2018	
Efficient Construction of Polyphase Sequences With Optimal Peak Sidelobe Level Growth	Montreal, QC, Canada
A. Bose, M. Soltanalian Presented in 5th IEEE Global Conference on Signal and Information Processing (GlobalSIP), Nov 2017	Nov. 2017
Non-Convex Shredded Signal Reconstruction via Sparsity Enhancement	New Orleans, USA
A. Bose, M. Soltanalian	Mar. 2017
• Presented in 42nd IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech and Signal Processing (ICASSP), March 201	7
PATENTS	
Learning-Based See-Through Sensing Suitable for Factory Automation	
P. Wang, TK. Akino, P. Orlik, A. Bose	2019
• US Patent and Trademark Office, Patent ID: 20210064013, Appl. No.: 16/552116	
Honors & Awards	

Chicago, IL, USA

Kolkata, India

Kolkata, India

Kolkata, India

Kolkata, India

2019 Signal Processing Society Chicago Chapter Appreciation, IEEE

2011 Winner, The Telegraph Knowhow Innovation Hub, INFOCOM 10-11

2014 Associate of the Month, Cognizant Technology Solutions

2008-2012 **Educational Scholarship**, Central Government of India

2010-2013 **Special Prize**, Science and Engineering Fair